Ankit Arora (Certified AWS SAA | PSM-1)

LinkedIn Profile | annkit87@gmail.com | +65-82472187 | Singapore

ABOUT ME

I am an **AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate** having 10+ years of software industry experience with strong analytical & technical skills. I have worked in multiple areas such as web development, application integrations, system architecture designing, team management & project management. I believe in lead by example practice & progressive SWOT analysis for professional growth.

TECHNICAL SKILLS (With hands-on experience):

- 1+ years: React JS, Redux, React Hooks, Node JS, Express, React JS, Wordpress, SugarCRM 5, vTigerCRM 6, Oracle (11g), MS SQL, Firebase, FCM, MongoDB, Socket.io
- **3+ years:** HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Codelgniter, Yii 2, Laravel 5, 7, AWS (EC2, SES, S3, SNS, RDS, SQS, API Gateway, Lambda, Elasticsearch), Java 8, J2EE, Java Servlets, Spring, Hibernate, JPA, Spring Boot, Redis, Memcache, Queues, Apache Solr
- 6+ years: PHP (5, 7), Drupal (7, 8), REST API (Basic Auth, OAuth2, API versioning, JWT), MySQL (5, 8), OOP, TDD, BDD, SOLID, DRY

VERSION CONTROL & DEVOPS: GIT, GITHUB, GITLAB, BITBUCKET, Composer (Dependency Manager), NPM, JENKINS, Continuous Integration (CI) / Continuous Deployment (CD), Docker

THIRD PARTY API's: Google Maps API, RETS API, Zillow API (Real Estate), Social Media (Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn) API, SMS Gateway (Nexmo, Twilio), Paypal, Xendit

WEB/ APPLICATION SERVERS: Apache Web Server, Nginx, Apache Tomcat

TOOLS & METHODOLOGIES: NetBeans, Eclipse, intelliJ, VS-Code, Jira, Slack, Scrum, Waterfall Approach, Agile Approach

OS: Linux (Ubuntu), Windows XP, 7, 8, 10, Mac OS (Mojave)

DATABASES: MySQL (5), Oracle (11g), MS SQL

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Solutions Architect Associate (<u>AWS SAA-C02</u>)
- Professional Scrum Master (<u>PSM-1</u>)

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS:

- System Architecture Design: Designed system architecture including database design as well as technology project architecture for multiple projects & defined various processes (HR, ERP, CRM, CMS, Accounts, IT) in the running systems to enhance their productivity.
- Scrum Master: Helped to understand scrum framework & its values to different teams in the organization. Make sure that all relevant events are happening within respective time bounds & only relevant & required members are participating in them. Exhibited the practice in teams to learn and improve as we grow.
- Multiple Domain Knowledge: Managed multiple domain projects (Health, Education, Insurance, eCommerce, Petroleum, Real Estate) with an ease to fulfill the end client needs in an impressive manner.
- **Team Management:** Groom development team (10+ members) to manage & deliver projects maintaining quality standards of the work within the deadline. Lead team of 10 + people by managing their work related activities and helped them to learn other professional development skills.
- Client Communication: Very comfortable to manage client communications. Managed verbal and written (chat & email) mode of communications in an effective manner.
- Project Management: Expertise in the Project Initiation, Planning, Execution, Quality Assurance & Closure. Along with that very good experience in Risk Management, Resource Management & Delivery Management.
- Global Exposure: Worked directly with a team of some of the big Singaporean clients like Parkway Pantai, Shell, Beckman Coulter Inc., Centurion, Sistic etc.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Equinix Singapore (Jul 2021 to present) — #22-03, 79 Robinson Rd, Singapore 068897, Singapore.

• Software Engineer IV, Jul 2021 to present

Industrial Electronics Pte Ltd (Sep 2019 to Jun 2021) — #05 Amazana Building, 50 MacPherson Road, Singapore.

• Senior Software Engineer, Sep 2019 to Jun 2021

Ranosys Technologies Pvt Ltd (Jan 2011 to Sep 2019) — E-141, Chatrala Circle, Sitapura, Jaipur.

- System Analyst, May 2016 to Sep 2019
- Team Lead (Web Application Development), May 2013 to Apr 2016
- **Software Engineer,** Jan 2011 to Apr 2013

PROJECT RESULTS

Worked as project manager, lead programmer and/or team member on dozens of projects. Delivered solution oriented services that consist of...

- **CMS Solutions:** Published visions of a large number of end clients to the market for promoting their business with CMS (Drupal, Wordpress) based solutions.
 - 1. **Site Management Portal (Digital Transformation)**: Provided a single portal for managing multiple sites (Wordpress/ Drupal) content & SEO trends to editors & publishers.
 - a. Role: Tech Lead + Lead Developer
 - i. Designed key architectural changes in terms of multiple sites & layout creation dynamically
 - ii. Designed architecture & develop API for content publishing workflow from portal (Drupal 8) to multiple sites (Wordpress/ Drupal)
 - b. **Technology Stack:** Drupal 8, PHP 7, Javascript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, React JS, Elasticsearch, Node Js, Socket.io
 - c. Database: MySQL
 - d. Third Party Integration: Google Charts API
 - 2. **Sistic Website Revamp (Booking Engine)**: Provided revamped website & mobile apps for better user experience & smooth ticket purchase experience. Designed & developed Drupal 8 based headless website using node & react js.
 - a. Role: System Architect + Lead Developer
 - i. Designed architecture for modules like advertisements, promotions, attractions & event
 - ii. Designed & developed the recommendation feature for showing most relevant events to users according to their site exploration activities
 - iii. Designed architecture for REST API's (consume in website & mobile apps)
 - iv. Designed architectural workflow for integration with their existing booking engine portal using React push events/ listeners
 - v. CI/CD implementation using GIT pipeline
 - b. **Technology Stack:** Drupal 8, PHP 7, Javascript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, React JS, Node Js, Express
 - c. Database: MySQL
 - d. Search API: Elasticsearch
- **Digitalization (System Automations):** Reduced their manual efforts by 90% with the provided automated system for managing their large & complex quotations and field service reports in an effective manner.
 - 1. Wheeler Butler Mobile Apps, Backend portal (WheelerButler Your Courier, On Demand)
 - a. Role: Lead Programmer
 - b. Technology Stack: Yii , PHP, Javascript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, APNS, GCM
 - c. **Database:** MySQL (Effective usage of scheduled Events)

- 2. **Beckman Coulter iPad Apps, Backend portal** (Beckman Coulter Inc. Provided very interactive & easy to use iPad apps to field service engineers of Beckman coulter team for managing their FSR very effectively.)
 - a. Role: Team Lead (System Architect + Manager)
 - b. Technology Stack: Laravel 5.4, PHP 7, Javascript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3
 - c. Database: MySQL
- Real Estate Business Solutions: A system which contains all the recent property info from Central Coast Regional MLS and provides various tools like comparative market analysis, pricing & equity retention calculator tools for helping the interested sellers.
 - 1. <u>Listing Launcher</u>
 - a. Role: Team Lead (Lead Programmer + Manager)
 - b. Technology Stack: Yii 2, PHP, Javascript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3
 - c. Database: MySQL (Effective usage of Views, Stored Procedures)
 - d. Third Party Integration: RETS API, Google MAPS API, Zillow API
- **eCommerce/ Retail Solutions:** Expanded businesses of various firms by giving them a very fast growing eCommerce based web (POS) as well as mobile app solutions (API Support).
 - 1. Dine Social Mobile Apps, Backend portal (Effective usage of Laravel queues for sending promotional emails, events & listener for table confirmation, cancellation notifications)
 - a. Role: Team Lead (System Architect + Lead Programmer)
 - b. Technology Stack: Laravel 5.3, PHP 7, Javascript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3
 - c. **Database:** MySQL (Effective usage of scheduled Events)
 - 2. The Aroma Group (Indonesia) Providing mobile apps for brands to list out their menus, promotions, ads & for customers to get a variety of food options nearby. Along with a web based backend for revenue related reports & KPI statistics. Digital Wallet design and Elasticsearch integration for fast & effective search.
 - a. Role: System Analyst (Lead Programmer)
 - b. **Technology Stack:** Laravel 5.6 (Lucid Architecture), PHP 7, Javascript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, FCM, Firebase Realtime databases, Elasticsearch
 - c. **Database:** MySQL 5.8 (Effective usage of scheduled Events)
 - d. Payment Integration: Xendit (Indonesia's payment solution)

Intranet Solutions:

- 1. Ranosys Intranet (Phase 1, 2) Helped our organisation's management, HR, TL and employees to manage their daily associated activities. There are a very essential set of modules to manage projects (which includes planning, execution, risk mitigation, QA, etc all phases), competencies, leave, daily updates, assets, resource planning, coding guidelines, internal claims, recruitments, etc.
 - a. Role: System Architect
 - b. **Technology Stack:** Codelgniter (Phase 1), Yii 2.0 (Phase 2), PHP, Javascript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3
 - c. **Database:** MySQL (Effective usage of Views, Stored Procedures)

- Centurion Corporation (Web based HRM portal) Prepared company specific portal to manage their employees & associated essential data like leaves, working days & shifts, salary setup, payroll, statistical reports, etc. more effectively.
 - a. Role: System Architect
 - b. **Responsibilities:** Designed database tables & ERD, Designed API Stubs & Prepared detail technical design documentation
 - c. **Technology Stack:** Spring Boot (REST API), Hibernate, Javascript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3
 - d. Database: MySQL
- Insurance Domain (Healthcare): Designed system architecture for mobile applications & web based specialist portal for Parkway Pantai one of the largest private healthcare providers in Asia. Also managed enhancements tasks for their existing system (as insurance provider) running from the last 10 years for multiple clients.
 - 1. My Health Wallet (Mobile Apps)
 - a. Role: System Architect
 - b. **Responsibilities:** Designed database tables & ERD, Designed API Stubs & Prepared detail technical design documentation
 - c. Database: MSSQL
 - 2. **SPOS** (Web based Specialist portal)
 - a. **Role:** System Architect
 - b. **Technology Stack:** Spring Boot (REST API), Spring Security, Hibernate, React.js, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3
 - c. **Responsibilities:** Designed database tables & ERD, Designed API Stubs & Prepared detail technical design documentation
 - d. Database: Oracle (11g)
- Energy & Petrochemical Domain: Designed system architecture for iPad applications & web backend portal (internal use) for providing ease to their onsite workshop engineers who attend multiple equipment for repair & services on a daily basis. Provided a very interactive & selection based interface for submitting their long list of checklist items for a single equipment going through various stages (Cleaning, Dismantling, Repari, Assembling, Testing).
 - 1. **Shell** (iPad Apps & web backend portal)
 - a. Role: System Architect
 - Technology Stack: Spring Boot (REST API), Hibernate, React.js, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3
 - c. Database: MySQL

EDUCATION

B.Tech (63%) Computer Science, 2010 (JECRC, Jaipur)12th (86%) Science (PCM), 2005 (St. Vivekananda Sr. Sec. School, Bikaner)10th (80%), 2003 (St. Vivekananda Sr. Sec. School, Bikaner)

LANGUAGES: English, Hindi